Joseph "Mike" Tallerico

Web Developer with a passion for code.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a web developer with skills in CSS, HTML, and JavaScript. I am passionate about writing code and building great web apps/sites that solve problems.

Continual education and keeping up with the latest technology trends are both critical to me. It isn't uncommon to find me coding through the weekends at my favorite coffee shop. Check out my most recent projects at talleri.co.

I look forward to applying my previous work experience in microelectronics to a career in web development.

CONTACT

Phone: **8453378141**

Address: 33 Spring Creek Dr. Apt. 404

Pleasant Valley, NY 12569

Website: talleri.co

Email: mike@talleri.co

TECH

Languages: JavaScript

Back-End Frameworks: Node/Express

Front-End Frameworks: React, Vue, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, Foundation

Databases: MongoDB **Other:** Gulp, Git, Bash

EXPERIENCE

Tallerico Design Company

FEBRUARY 2017 TO PRESENT

Owner

- Branding Design.
- Print Design.
- Web Design/Web Development.
- Shopify Theme Development.

Valley Christian Church

AUGUST 2014 TO PRESENT

Technical/Creative Arts Director

- Designed live production Audio/Video/Lighting system for our mobile campus.
- Managed over 60 Technical Volunteer teams across two locations and one fulltime staff member.
- Saved organization \$90,000 by installing equipment in house as opposed to paying an outside vendor.
- Successfully created multimedia programming in house using the Adobe Creative Suite of programs.
- Launched 3 new websites.
- Managed all live production weekend events as well as online streaming events.
- Small Group Leader.
- Senior Executive Team Member.

Applied Materials

JULY 2006 TO AUGUST 2014

Specialist

- Used schematics and documents to fix complex mechanical, electrical and pneumatic issues in a fast paced environment while on customer site.
- Created best known methods on first in world equipment and rolled out learning to worldwide field service teams.
- Took part in Kaizen events in order to reduce customer down time and to streamline preventative maintenance activities.
- Increased profit margins on consumable parts by decreasing waste and cutting cost.
- Created pricing on consumable part changes in order to maximize profit and to cover our cost.
- Successfully trained new engineers on equipment.
- Installed systems in a timely and efficient manner.
- Worked with customer to schedule preventative maintenance activities as well as kept open communication about the various states of the equipment and when it could be expected to be back into full production mode.
- Presented monthly presentations to customer top management to make them aware of trending issues and major machine down time drivers.
- Supervised 2nd Shift Engineering Team.
- Experimented with continual improvement projects to better the equipment for our customer.
- Supported Full Service Contract on Endura/Producer/EPI/Centura systems.

ASML November 2005 to July 2006

Customer Service Engineer

- Serviced and supported semiconductor photolithography machinery for National Semiconductor.
- Accurately maintained and updated documents recording various tasks completed.
- Served as a company liaison with the customer to ensure proper warranty and contract specifications were met or exceeded.

Applied Materials

August 2004 to November 2005

Customer Engineer Level 1

- Served integral part in decreasing preventative maintenance downtime by 25% through implementing new streamlined procedures and checklists.
- Successfully managed senior engineer responsibilities within 3 months of joining the company.
- Collaborated with colleagues to accurately update and maintain parts inventory, effectively decreasing costs for the customer.
- Employee of the quarter for Global IBM team.

Stanley Electric

SEPTEMBER 2001 TO AUGUST 2004

Maintenance Technician Intern

- Was chosen from a list of applicants from my school to become a paid intern that
 assisted engineers in the building and maintaining of manufacturing equipment
 used in the process of building headlights and taillights for Honda, Nissan and
 Acura
- Programmed PLC controllers aiding in automated manufacturing tasks.
- Selected to collaborate with an engineer in the building of a new manufacturing line for the Honda Odyssey.

• Troubleshot issues related to all manner of manufacturing machinery.

EDUCATION

DeVry University

JULY **2001** TO **A**UGUST OF **2004**

Bachelors of Science in Electronics Engineering Technology

- Technology integration and analysis.
- Microprocessor architecture, controls and mechatronics.
- Electronic circuits and devices.
- Digital systems and signal processing.
- Hardware description languages.
- Programmable logic devices.
- Complex problem-solving.

Treehouse Novmeber of 2017 to Present

Full Stack Javascript Techdegree

Training in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript with a heavy focus on JavaScript libraries such as React and Node.